Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Vernon W. Lippard, 1936-1976; Accession 1979-A-007
  - I. General
    - Machine and electronic shops, 1956-1959 (Box 14, Folder 209)
    - Macy Foundation, 1930-1943 (Box 14, Folder 210)
    - Maintenance, 1949-1959 (Box 14, Folder 211)
    - Maintenance: budget, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 212)
    - Massachusettes General Hospital: Harvard Medical School, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 215)
    - Medical Affairs, Division of, 1948-1952 (Box 15, Folder 216)
    - Medical Alumni Bulletin: response to alumni newsletter, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 217)
    - Medical area: aerial view photograph, 1952-1964 (Box 15, Folder 220)
    - Medical deferment student identification cards, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 221)
    - Medical education, 1939-1943 (Box 16, Folder 222)
    - Medical Education Program at. Yale reprint from Connecticut Magazine, undated (Box 16, Folder 223)
    - Medical motion picture films, 1939-1951 (Box 16, Folder 224)
    - Medical Physics Study Unit, 1948-1952 (Box 16, Folder 225)
    - Merck and Company, Incorporated, 1940-1950 (Box 16, Folder 226)
    - Mexican Congress of Medicine, 1946-1948 (Box 16, Folder 227)
    - Miami, University of: School of Medicine, 1954-1961 (Box 16, Folder 228)
    - Michigan-Yale-Phillips Educational Corporation, 1953-1955 (Box 16, Folder 229)
    - Miscellaneous: Inquiries, suggestions, "no reply", requests, etc., 1939-1951 (Box 16, Folder 230 - 231)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1960 (Box 17, Folder 232 - 238)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 239)
    - Miscellaneous: organizations, 1957-1963 (Box 18, Folder 240)
    - Miscellaneous: policies, 1954-1957 (Box 18, Folder 241)
    - Monkey colony: Dr. Van Wagenen, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 242)
    - Murphy, Charles B.G., 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 243)
    - Muscular Dystrophy Association of America, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 244)
    - National Board: results, 1953-1960 (Box 18, Folder 245)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 246)
    - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1941-1952 (Box 18, Folder 247 - 248)
    - National Foundation for Medical Research, 1932-1952 (Box 18, Folder 249 - 250)
    - National Fund for Medical Education Incorporated, 1949-1952 (Box 18, Folder 251)
    - National Fund for Medical Education, Incorporated, 1953-1954 (Box 19, Folder 252)
    - National Institute for Neurological Disease, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 253)
    - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 254)
    - National Society for Medical Research, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 255)
    - Neurological Study Unit, 1940-1951 (Box 19, Folder 256)
    - New Britain Hospital, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 257)
    - Newcomers Club, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 258)
    - New Haven Medical Association, 1939-1948 (Box 19, Folder 259)
    - New Haven Register: miscellaneous articles, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 260)
    - New Haven Safty Council, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 261)
    - New York State: University College of Medicine at New York City, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 262)
    - North Carolina at Chapel Hill, University of: choice of specialties in Medicine, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 263)
    - Norwalk General Hospital (Box 19, Folder 264)
    - Nursing, School of, 1941-1950 (Box 19, Folder 265)
    - Nutrition Foundation, Inc., 1949 (Box 19, Folder 266)
    - Ohio, State of: Interim Commission on Education Beyond High School, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 267)
    - Organon, Incorporated, 1949-1952 (Box 19, Folder 268)
    - Ouellette, Gerard A., 1956 (Box 19, Folder 269)
    - Pan American Bureau: Regional Poliomyelitis Center, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 270)
    - Parking problems, 1953-1965 (Box 19, Folder 271)
    - Patents, 1940-1951 (Box 19, Folder 273)
    - Personal problems, 1953-1960 (Box 20, Folder 274)
    - Pharmaceutical companies, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 275)
    - Pharmacology dedication, 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 276)
    - Ph.D. Committee for the Biological Sciences, 1942-1952 (Box 20, Folder 277)
    - Physical Medicine, 1943-1952 (Box 20, Folder 278)
    - Positions available, 1950-1952 (Box 20, Folder 279)
    - Post graduate education, 1940-1952 (Box 20, Folder 280 - 283)
    - Preceptorship Program, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 285)
    - Preclinical Sciences, Committe on, 1939-1952 (Box 21, Folder 286 - 287)
    - Preparedness for Child Birth Program, 1962-1965 (Box 21, Folder 288)
    - Presidents Committe on Education Beyond High School, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 289)
    - Procedure for processing faculty, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 290)
    - Professorship of psychiatry: Charles B.G. Murphy, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 291)
    - Promotions and appointments, 1946-1951 (Box 21, Folder 292)
    - Psychatry, Committee on, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 293 - 294)
    - Public Health Nursing Graduate Program, undated (Box 21, Folder 295)
    - Public Health Service: United States grant and fellowship information, 1950-1952 (Box 21, Folder 296)
    - Publications, 1940-1949 (Box 21, Folder 297)
    - Publications resulting from student thesis work, 1952-56 (Box 22, Folder 298)
    - Questionnaires: Association of American Medical Colleges, 1950-1952 (Box 22, Folder 299)
    - Radiation hazards, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 300)
    - Radio-active Isotopes Committee, 1947-1952 (Box 22, Folder 301)
    - Receiving and maintenance building, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 303)
    - Recommendation for appointment: Teaching positions and faculty rank forms, undated (Box 22, Folder 304)
    - Recommendation, form B: new appointments of instructors, clinical instructors and research assistants, undated (Box 22, Folder 306)
    - Recommendatlon letters, 1949-1952 (Box 22, Folder 307)
    - Red Cross Blood Bank, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 308)
    - Rehabilitation Study Unit, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 309)
    - Renthe-Fink from Germany: Cancer prevention in United States, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 310)
    - Reorganization plans: School of Medicine and New Haven Hospital, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 311)
    - Reports of research in progress, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 312)
    - Requests: miscellaneous, 1947-1949 (Box 22, Folder 313)
    - Requisitions: supplies and materials, 1950-1952 (Box 22, Folder 314)
    - Reserve Officers Training Corp (ROTC): proposed unit at School of Medicine, 1947-1952 (Box 23, Folder 315)
    - Residency in Occupational Medicine: proposed, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 316)
    - Room space: Medical School, 1952-1959 (Box 23, Folder 318)
    - Russian Poliomyelitis: Tea party, Beaumont room, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 319)
    - Salter, William Thomas, 1941-1945 (Box 23, Folder 320)
    - Schering Corporation, 1949-1952 (Box 23, Folder 322)
    - Scholarships and Fellowships, Connnittee on, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 323)
    - Scholarship funds, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 324)
    - Scientific Research and Development, Office of, 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 325)
    - Selective Service and Veterans Affairs, Office of, 1944-1950 (Box 23, Folder 326)
    - Sesquicentennial celebration, 1959-1961 (Box 23, Folder 327 - 332)
    - Sesquicentennial celebration: news releases, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 333)
    - Sesquicentennial celebration: publicity and mailing, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 334 - 335)
    - Sherrill, Henry K.: Bishop, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 337)
    - Shindell, Sidney: consultant in medical jurisprudence, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 338)
    - Sigma Xi, 1942-1965 (Box 24, Folder 339)
    - Silliman lectures, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 340)
    - Slaughterhouse problems, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 341)
    - Sloan-Kettering Institute, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 342)
    - Smith, Kline and French Laboratories, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 343)
    - Space requirements, 1952-1954 (Box 25, Folder 344 - 345)
    - Sterling Hall of Medicine: expansion of C wing, 1954-1958 (Box 25, Folder 346)
    - Sterling Nursing Dormitory, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 347)
    - Sterling power plant addition, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 348)
    - Stone, Leon S.: portrait unveiling, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 349)
    - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1946-1951 (Box 25, Folder 350)
    - Student Council, 1955-1964 (Box 25, Folder 351)
    - Students: medical schecule for entering, 1952-1964 (Box 25, Folder 352)
    - Students: miscellaneous: lists, memoranda, 1939-1951 (Box 25, Folder 353)
    - Student problems, 1957-1960 (Box 25, Folder 354)
    - Student research program, 1947-1965 (Box 25, Folder 355)
    - Student statistics, 1949-1951 (Box 25, Folder 356)
    - Student tea hostess schedule, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 357)
    - Sugar Research Foundation, Incorporated, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 358)
    - Teaching program, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 359)
    - Treasurer's Office, 1937-1952 (Box 25, Folder 360)
    - Tropical medicine, 1942-1945 (Box 26, Folder 362)
    - Trudeau Sanitorium, 1947-1949 (Box 26, Folder 363)
    - United States Army: scholarships, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 364)
    - United States Color Film Printing and Processing Laboratories, New Haven, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 365)
    - United States Department of Agriculture: Plum Island Animal Disease Laboratory, 1956-1959 (Box 26, Folder 366)
    - United States Public Health Service, 1940-1967 (Box 26, Folder 367 - 368)
    - University Board of Health, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 369)
    - University Council: Committee on Medical Affairs, 1947-1956 (Box 26, Folder 370 - 372)
    - University Council: Committee on MedicalÂ· Affairs, 1957-1959 (Box 27, Folder 373 - 374)
    - University News Bureau, 1943-1952 (Box 27, Folder 375 - 376)
    - University Service Bureau Variety Club, 1939-1952 (Box 27, Folder 377)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital: Washington, D.C., 1947-1951 (Box 27, Folder 378)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital: New York, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 379)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital: Newington, Connecticut, 1952-1956 (Box 27, Folder 380)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital: Ad Hoc Committee on Relations Between Veterans and Medical Schools, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 381)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital: Reprints, Research and Education Committee, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 382)
    - Veterans application for admission to Yale School of Nedicine, 1950 (Box 27, Folder 383)
    - Virginia, University of, 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 384)
    - Visitation reuort: Weiskotten, Herman, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 385)
    - Visitors, 1963-1964 (Box 27, Folder 386)
    - Visitors and lecturers, 1953-1958 (Box 28, Folder 387 - 388)
    - Visitors: proposed visits, tours, 1940-1942 (Box 28, Folder 389)
    - Webster, Noah: potrait unveiling, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 390)
    - Yale Corporation, 1940-1950 (Box 28, Folder 394)
    - Yale in China Association, 1946-1961 (Box 28, Folder 395)
    - Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1943-1963 (Box 29, Folder 396 - 397)
    - Yale Medical Democrats, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 398)
    - Yale Medical Education, Program of, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 399)
    - Yale Medical Library, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 400 - 401)
    - Yale Medical Library bulletins and reports, 1940-1952 (Box 29, Folder 402 - 403)
    - Yale Medical Library: candidates for librarian, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 404)
    - Yale Medical Library, Committee on, 1941-1952 (Box 30, Folder 405 - 406)
    - Yale Medical Society, 1939-1967 (Box 30, Folder 407 - 408)
    - Yale System: statement, 1953-1956 (Box 30, Folder 409)
    - Yale University: miscellaneous memoranda, 1940-1952 (Box 30, Folder 410)
    - Yale University: personnel, 1940-1952 (Box 30, Folder 411)
    - Yerkes Biological Library, 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 412)
    - Yerkes Laboratory: primate biology, 1942-1951 (Box 30, Folder 413)
  - IV. MINUTES OF BOARD OF PERMANENT OFFICERS, SCHOOL OF MEDICINE; MINUTES OF EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE, SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, 1947-1968
    - Board of Permanent Officers
      - 1947-1948 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - 1948 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - 1949 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 44, Folder 4 - 6)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - 1954-1956 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - 1960 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - 1961 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - 1962 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - 1963 (Box 46, Folder 15 - 16)
      - 1964 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - 1965 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - 1966 (Box 46, Folder 19)
      - 1967 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - 1968 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Executive Committee
      - 1947-1948 (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 24 - 25)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 47, Folder 27 - 28)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 48, Folder 29)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 30)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 31)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 48, Folder 32)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 48, Folder 33)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 48, Folder 34)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 48, Folder 35)
      - 1960 (Box 49, Folder 36)
      - 1961 (Box 49, Folder 37 - 38)
      - 1962 (Box 49, Folder 39)
      - 1963 (Box 49, Folder 40 - 41)
      - 1964 (Box 50, Folder 42)
      - 1965 (Box 50, Folder 43)
      - 1966 (Box 50, Folder 44)
      - 1967 (Box 50, Folder 45)
      - 1968 (Box 50, Folder 46)
  - V. MEDICAL DEPARTMENTS: CORRESPONDENCE, 1937-1967
    - Anatomy, Department of, 1948-1963 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Animal care, 1953-1962 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Applicants for faculty and other positions, 1948-1956 (Box 51, Folder 3 - 7)
    - Applicants for faculty and other positions, 1957-1963 (Box 52, Folder 8-9)
    - Applicants: job openings at other hospitals and universities, 1955-1964 (Box 52, Folder 10 - 11)
    - Bacteriology, Department of, 1948 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Biochemistry, Department of, 1953-1962 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Biophysics, Department of, 1955-1960 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Child Study Center, 1953-1963 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Dermatology, 1952-1962 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Epidemeology and Public Health, 1960-1967 (Box 53, Folder 17 - 21)
    - Genetics, Deparment of, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Health, Department of: Division of Student Mental Hygiene, 1951-1956 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - History of Medicine, 1951-1958 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - History of Science and Medicine, Department of, 1959-1961 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - History of Science and Medicine: Professorship Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 26)
    - Human Relations, Institute of: floor plans and sketches, undated (Box 54, Folder 27)
    - Internal Medicine, Department of, 1947-1952 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - Medical Illustration, Department of, 1942-1962 (Box 54, Folder 29)
    - Medical Social Services, 1940-1949 (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Memoranda from the Dean, 1962-1967 (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Mental Hospital Administration Program, 1954-1955 (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - Microbiology, Committee on, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Microbiology, Department of, 1941-1961 (Box 54, Folder 34 - 35)
    - Microbiology: professorship, 1959-1961 (Box 55, Folder 36)
    - Neurology, 1940-1941 (Box 55, Folder 37)
    - Nutrition, Department of, 1944-1951 (Box 55, Folder 38)
    - Nutrition Laboratory, 1952-1960 (Box 55, Folder 39)
    - Obstetrics and Gynecology, Department of, 1941-1961 (Box 55, Folder 40 - 42)
    - Obstetrics and Gynecology: professorship, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 43)
    - Occupational Medicine and Hygiene, Institute of, 1948-1952 (Box 55, Folder 44)
    - Oncology, Section of, 1947-1952 (Box 56, Folder 45)
    - Ophthamo1ogy, 1954-1963 (Box 56, Folder 46)
    - Orthopedic surgery director: applicants, 1957 (Box 56, Folder 47)
    - Otolaryngology, Section of, 1953-1963 (Box 56, Folder 48)
    - Pathology, Department of, 1947-1961 (Box 56, Folder 49 - 51)
    - Pathology: professorship, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 52)
    - Pediatrics, Department of, 1939-1963 (Box 57, Folder 53 - 55)
    - Pharmacology, Department of, 1947-1963 (Box 57, Folder 56 - 58)
    - Pharmacology: professorship, 1937-1940 (Box 57, Folder 59)
    - Physiological Chemistry, Department of, 1939-1951 (Box 57, Folder 60)
    - Physiology, Department of, 1946-1963 (Box 58, Folder 61 - 62)
    - Physiology, Chairmanship of, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 63)
    - Physiology, Laboratory of Applied, 1955 (Box 58, Folder 64)
    - Physiology: Medical Physics Unit, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 65)
    - Preventive Medicine, 1946-1960 (Box 58, Folder 66 - 68)
    - Primate Biology Laboratories: tenth annual report, 1938-1939 (Box 58, Folder 69)
    - Primate Biology Laboratories: eleventh annual report (Box 58, Folder 70)
    - Primate Biology Laboratories: twelfth annual report, 1940-1941 (Box 58, Folder 71)
    - Psychiatric Institute, 1952-1967 (Box 59, Folder 72 - 79)
    - Psychiatry, Department of, 1952-1963 (Box 60, Folder 80)
    - Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 81)
    - Public Health: candidates for professorship, 1958-1959 (Box 60, Folder 82)
    - Public Health, Department ofÂ, 1948-1962 (Box 60, Folder 83 - 86)
    - Public Health: occupational health, 1952-1958 (Box 60, Folder 87)
    - Radiology: candidates for the professorship, 1957-1958 (Box 61, Folder 88 - 89)
    - Radiology: conference, 1957 (Box 61, Folder 90)
    - Radiology, Department of, 1952-1960 (Box 61, Folder 91 - 92)
    - Surgery: general, 1947-1966 (Box 61, Folder 93 - 95)
    - Surgery: Anesthesiology, 1953-1963 (Box 61, Folder 96)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: Austin, W. Gerald, 1965 (Box 61, Folder 97)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: Chase, Robert A., 1964-1965 (Box 61, Folder 98)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: Lindskog, G.E., 1952-1964 (Box 61, Folder 99 - 100)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: MacLean, Lloyd, 1964-1965 (Box 62, Folder 101)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of McDermott, Hilliam V., 1962-1965 (Box 62, Folder 102)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: Orloff, Marshall, 1953-1965 (Box 62, Folder 103 - 104)
    - Surgery, chairmanship of: Spencer, Frank C., 1964-1965 (Box 62, Folder 105)
    - Surgery: Johns Hopkins reports, 1953-1964 (Box 62, Folder 107)
    - Surgery: miscellaneous, 1964-1966 (Box 62, Folder 108 - 110)
  - VI. ASSOCIATION OF MEDICAL COLLEGES: CORRESPONDENCE, 1940-1966
    - Administrative Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 63, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Administrative Institute: hospital relations, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Institute: parent university relations, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Annual meetings, 1953-1962 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Atlantic City talk, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Borden award-, 1953-1965 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Developments Grant Program: Evaluation Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Education for Physicians in Industry: conference, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Educational Research and Services, Committee on Evaluation and Measurement, Subcommittee on, 1956-1958 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee, 1955-1959 (Box 64, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Executive Council meeting, 1952-1954 (Box 64, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Expense account, 1955-1957 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Faculty: official reg-istry poll, 1953-1960 (Box 64, Folder 17 - 19)
    - Faculty, estimated required size of: Questionnair, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Federal Health Programs, Committee on, 1962-1963 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Financial Aid to Xedical Education, Committee on, 1956-1962 (Box 65, Folder 22 - 25)
    - Flexner award, 1957-1964 (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - Foreign Graduate Students, Committee on, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - Foreign licensing problem, 1954-1956 (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - General, 1940-1954 (Box 66, Folder 29 - 35)
    - General, 1954-1965 (Box 67, Folder 36 - 42)
    - Intern-Resident Survey at Yale-New - Haven Hospital, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 43)
    - International Relations in Medical Education, Committee on, 1961-1964 (Box 68, Folder 44 - 50)
    - Journal of Medical Education, 1952-1964 (Box 69, Folder 51 - 53)
    - Medical Education, Liaison Committee on, 1953-1966 (Box 69, Folder 54)
    - Medical Education for National Defense and Planning for National Emergency, Committees on, 1953-1959 (Box 69, Folder 55)
    - Medical Specialties- Advisory Board for, 1961-1963 (Box 70, Folder 56)
    - Medical Student Research Training Program, 1962 (Box 70, Folder 57)
    - Meeting at Lake Placid Club, 1950 (Box 70, Folder 58)
    - Memoranda to deans from directors, 1958-1961 (Box 70, Folder 59 - 62)
    - Memoranda to deans from directors, 1962-1966 (Box 71, Folder 63 - 67)
    - National Society for Medical Research, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 68)
    - New office location, 1954-1955 (Box 71, Folder 69)
    - Presidential address (V.W. Lippard), 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 70)
    - Regional deans' meeting, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 71)
    - Selective Service System on doctors' draft, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 72)
    - Straight Internship Program, 1957 (Box 72, Folder 73)
    - Student affairs, 1962-1964 (Box 72, Folder 74)
    - Teaching Institute, 1953-1962 (Box 72, Folder 75 - 82)
    - Teaching Institutes and Special Studies, Committee on, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 83)
    - Veterans Administration-Medical School Relations, Committee on, 1959-1963 (Box 72, Folder 84)
    - Yale University presurvey questionnaire, 1958 (Box 72, Folder 85 - 86)
  - VII. CORRESPONDENCE WITH VARIOUS MEDICAL ORGANIZATIONS, 1940-1966
    - Accredation of Hospitals, Committee on (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Council- on Medical Education (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Air Force, Department of (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Alpha Epsilon Delta (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - American Acadamy of General Practice (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - American Acadamy of Occupational Medicine (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - American Acadamy of Ophtamology and Otolaryngology (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - American Acadamy of Pediatrics (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - American Association of Theological Schools (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - American Cancer Society (Box 73, Folder 11 - 13)
    - American Cancer Society: biostatistics (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - American Cancer Society: program on "The Roll of Viruses in Cancer" in honor of Dr. Duran-Reynals (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - American College of Cardiology: American Heart Association, Incorporated (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - American College of Chest Physicians (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - American College of Physicians (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - American College of Surgeons (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - American Council on Education (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - American Federation for Clinical Research (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - American Foundation Studies (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - American Fund for Psychaiatry (Box 74, Folder 23 - 28)
    - American Hospital of Istanbul, 1954 (Box 74, Folder 29)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 30)
    - American Medical Association, 1940-1946 (Box 74, Folder 31 - 32)
    - American Medical Association, 1947-1965 (Box 75, Folder 33 - 38)
    - American Medical Association: The AMA Washington Letter, 1953-1955 (Box 75, Folder 39)
    - American Medical Association: annual meetings, 1961-1963 (Box 75, Folder 40)
    - American Medical Association: Capital Clinic reports, 1952 (Box 75, Folder 41)
    - American Medical Association: Committee on Medical Problems, 1953-1965 (Box 75, Folder 42)
    - American Medical Association Committee on Research of the Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry, 1953-1955 (Box 75, Folder 43)
    - American Medical Association: Congress on Medical Education on Licensure, 1955-1958 (Box 75, Folder 44)
    - American Medical Association: Conference on Relationship Between Voluntary Health Insurance and Medical Education, 1952 (Box 75, Folder 45)
    - American Medical Association: Council on Medical Education, 1952-1964 (Box 76, Folder 46)
    - American Medical Association: Council on Medical Service, 1956 (Box 76, Folder 47)
    - American Medical Association: Council on National Emergency Service, 1952 (Box 76, Folder 48)